# **Hemant Vasant Disale**

hemantdisale2016@u.northwestern.edu | linkedin.com/in/hemantdisale | 224-392-8542

#### **SUMMARY**

Master of Engineering Management with experience & expertise in engineering project management, financial & root cause analysis, value analysis (VA), driveline & chassis technology. Solid organizational skills with ability to coordinate multiple projects simultaneously, work under pressure and meet deadlines under time constraints.

#### **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University | Masters in Engineering Management | Evanston, IL | CGPA: 3.79/4.0

Dec 2016

Course highlights: Finance & Accounting, Marketing, Decision Tools, Leadership & Organizational behavior, Negotiation skills, Operations Excellence, Strategic management, Project & Supply chain management.

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology | B.E. in Production Engineering | Pune, India | CGPA: 8.58/10

May 2011

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Summer Intern – Consultant | Schneider Electric | United States

Jun 2016-Aug 2016

 Conducted & produced a financial analysis report identifying CAPEX, revenue streams, NPV, IRR, ROI, that is being assessed for implementation of a solar+storage+EVcharging microgrid project by collecting & cleansing energy load data, integrating & generating HOMER, DER-CAM models for clients like Argonne National Lab & Northwestern University

# Senior Engineer – Off highway systems | ZF India Private Limited | Pune, India

Jan 2013-Aug 2015

- Led & coordinated engineering projects between global cross functional teams focusing on value analysis (VA) & competition benchmarking, resulting in 5% cost reduction on overall transmission BOM.
- Directed cost reduction workshops, planned and monitored the implementation of cost reduction ideas in phases considering the technical and commercial validation with suppliers, customers and internal engineering team.
- Improved & led product line failure handling process as a single point contact to OEM customers by implementing a master sheet resulting in streamlining of root cause analysis process, timely resolution of customer issues & continuous improvement.
- Supported customer interactions for duty cycle measurements, product allocation & sign-offs as an application engineer.

# International Post-Graduate Trainee | ZF Friedrichshafen AG | Germany

Oct 2011-Dec 2012

- Formulated & implemented a business process model for business development activities between cross-national locations using workflow chart & inputs from different process owners resulting in tracking & streamlining of business activities.
- Conducted clutch calculations & standardization project on off-highway system transmission using excel & Pro-Engineer resulting in master sheet for clutch safety factor calculation & potential cost savings from standardization of components.
- Investigated the feasibility of localizing a transmission in India in collaboration with global cross functional teams by conducting market study, identifying CAPEX, cost & revenue streams resulting in a business case aiding effective decision making.

Global ZF project management system certificate | ZF (China) Investment Co., Ltd | Shanghai, China

Nov 2014

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Capital budgeting analysis | Northwestern University | Evanston, IL

Apr 2016-Jun 2016

- Developed a discounted cash flow (DCF) model for Tesla's Model 3 & Facebook's Oculus Rift project, resulting in NPV and IRR.
- Conducted risk analysis using decision tree and @risk simulation resulting in risk adjusted NPV and go/ no go recommendations.

# Project estimation and valuation | Northwestern University | Evanston, IL

Jan 2016-Mar 2016

• Analyzed the feasibility & created a project plan for development of a new drug considering the regulatory approval process, revenue potential, risk analysis and mitigation, probability of commercial success resulting in a go/ no go recommendation.

### **SUPPLEMENTAL SKILLS**

- Technical, Business & Soft Skills: Problem solving, critical thinking, data analysis & interpretation, decision making, accounting, automotive technology, design & development, financial modeling, analytical problem solving, manufacturing, application engineering, project planning, project management, negotiating, conflict management, delegation, reporting, collaborating, leadership, adaptability, effective communicator, multitasking, presentation
- Technology: Pro-Engineer, Axalant, Microsoft office suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), MS project 2013, Tableau
- Leadership & volunteering: Pro-Engineer software trainer (2010); Led a team of fellow students to design departmental magazine (2009)
- Languages: English (Fluent), Hindi (Native), German (Intermediate)